Guide to the Otto Rank Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Arranged Manuscripts
  - Subseries IV.1: Chronological Series, 1903 - 1939
    - Rank, Otto & Ferenczi, S&or Entwicklungsziele, [n.p.], 1924, (24 page a.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 203)
    - Rank, Otto & Ferenczi, S&or Entwicklungsziele. Notes., [n.p.], 1924, (40 page a.ms.) (Box 15, Folder 204)
    - Rank, Otto Das Trauma der Geburt. First draft., [n.p.], 1924, (80 page a.ms.) (Box 16, Folder 205)
    - Rank, Otto Das Trauma der Geburt. Intro, ch. 1-6, [n.p.], 1924, (140 page a.ms. & t.ms.) (Box 16, Folder 206)
      [See Manuscript Flat Box 169]
    - Rank, Otto Das Trauma der Geburt. Ch. 7-11., [n.p.], 1924, (130 page a.ms.) (Box 16, Folder 207)
    - Rank, Otto Das Trauma der Geburt, [n.p.], 1924, (70 page t.ms.) (Box 16, Folder 208)
    - Rank, Otto Das Trauma der Geburt, [n.p.], 1924, (55 page t.ms.) (Box 16, Folder 209)
    - Rank, Otto Das Trauma der Geburt. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1924, (16 page a.ms.) (Box 16, Folder 210)
    - Rank, Otto Das Trauma der Geburt. Loose notes and clippings, [n.p.], 1924, (14 page t.ms. & newspapers) (Box 16, Folder 211)
    - Rank, Otto Das Trauma der Geburt. Notebook., [n.p.], 1924, (46 page a.ms.) (Box 16, Folder 212)
      [This is a bound leather notebook.]
    - Rank, Otto Das Trauma der Geburt. Clippings., (20 page newspapers) (Box 16, Folder 213)
    - Rank, Otto Sexualitat und Schuldgefuhl. English trans., [n.p.], 1926, (28 page t.ms. (carbon)) (Box 17, Folder 214)
    - Rank, Otto Sexualitat und Schuldgeful. Notes., [n.p.], 1926, (1 page a.ms.) (Box 17, Folder 215)
    - Rank, Otto Teh Practical bearing of psychoanalysis. German orig. & English trans., [n.p.], 1926, (100 page a.ms. & t.ms.) (Box 17, Folder 216)
    - Rank, Otto The practical bearing..., [n.p.], 1926, (50 page t.ms.) (Box 17, Folder 217)
    - Rank, Otto Technik der Psychoanalyse. Part I., [n.p.], 1926, (20 p (incomplete). t.ms. ) (Box 17, Folder 218)
    - Rank, Otto Technik der Psychoanalyse I, [n.p.], 1926, (130 page a.ms.) (Box 17, Folder 219)
      [See Manuscript Flat Box 171]
    - Rank, Otto Technik der Psychoanalyse, II, [n.p.], 1926, (140 page a.ms.) (Box 17, Folder 220)
    - Rank, Otto Technik der Psychoanalyse, III, [n.p.], 1926, (45 page a.ms. & t.ms.) (Box 17, Folder 221)
    - Rank, Otto Technik der Psychoanalyse, II, [n.p.], 1929, (110 page t.ms.) (Box 17, Folder 222)
    - Rank, Otto Technik der Psychoanalyse, III. Page proof., [n.p.], 1931, (135 page t.ms.) (Box 17, Folder 223)
    - Rank, Otto Technik der Psychoanalyze, I & III. Notes., [n.p.], 1926-1939, (10 page a.ms.) (Box 17, Folder 224)
    - Rank, Otto Technik der Psychoanalse. English trans., [n.p.], 1926, (65 page t.ms.) (Box 17, Folder 225)
    - Rank, Otto Technik der Psychoanalyse, II. English trans., [n.p.], 1929, (72 page t.ms.) (Box 17, Folder 226)
    - Rank, Otto Technik der Psychoanalyse, III. English trans., [n.p.], 1931, (13 page t.ms. (carbon)) (Box 17, Folder 227)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part I. Draft., [n.p.], 1927, (22 page a.ms.) (Box 18, Folder 228)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part I. Intro., [n.p.], 1927, (100 page a.ms. & t.ms.) (Box 18, Folder 229)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part I. Genet. Teil., [n.p.], 1927, (32 page a.ms. & t.ms.) (Box 18, Folder 230)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part I. Psych. Mechanismen., [n.p.], 1927, (47 page a.ms.) (Box 18, Folder 231)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part I. Intro., [n.p.], 1927, (65 page t.ms.) (Box 18, Folder 232)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part I. Genetischer Teil., [n.p.], 1927, (32 page t.ms.) (Box 18, Folder 233)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part I. Physique Mechanismen., [n.p.], 1927, (36 page t.ms.) (Box 18, Folder 234)
    - Rank, Otto Gentische Psychologie. Part I., [n.p.], 1927, (100 page t.ms.) (Box 18, Folder 235)
      [Carbons]
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part I., [n.p.], 1927, (17 page t.ms.) (Box 18, Folder 236)
      [Page proof]
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part I. 2 unbound copies., [n.p.], 1927, (322 page t.ms.) (Box 18, Folder 237)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part I. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1927, (75 page a.ms.) (Box 18, Folder 238)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part I. English translation., [n.p.], 1927, (52 page t.ms.) (Box 18, Folder 239)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part I. English translation., [n.p.], 1927, (265 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 19, Folder 240)
      [O.R.A. 1984]
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. English translation., [n.p.], 1927, (52 page t.ms. (carbon)) (Box 19, Folder 241)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie., (45 page a.ms.) (Box 19, Folder 242)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part II. Intro, ch. 2., [n.p.], 1928, (45 page a.ms. & t.ms.) (Box 19, Folder 243)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part II., [n.p.], 1928, (108 p (10 p carbons). t.ms.) (Box 19, Folder 244)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie. Part II., [n.p.], 1928, (75 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 19, Folder 245)
    - Rank, Otto Die Geburt der Invidualitat, [n.p.], 22 Aug. 1927, (3 page a.ms.) (Box 19, Folder 246)
    - Rank, Otto Realitat und Berusstsein, [n.p.], 30 Aug 1927, (4 page a.ms.) (Box 19, Folder 247)
    - Rank, Otto Wahrheit und Wirklichkeit. (Part III of Genestische Psych.), [n.p.], 1929, (100 page a.ms.) (Box 20, Folder 248)
    - Rank, Otto Wahrheit und Wirklichkeit, [n.p.], 1929, (25 page a.ms.) (Box 20, Folder 249)
    - Rank, Otto Wahrheit und Wirklichkeit. Ch. 5, 6., [n.p.], 1929, (35 page t.ms.) (Box 20, Folder 250)
    - Rank, Otto Wahrheit und Wirklichkeit, [n.p.], 1929, (100 page t.ms.) (Box 20, Folder 251)
    - Rank, Otto Wahrheit und Wirklichkeit. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1929, (4 page a.ms.) (Box 20, Folder 252)
    - Rank, Otto Wahrheit und Wirklichkeit. Psych. Abstracts., [n.p.], July 1929, (3 page a.ms.) (Box 20, Folder 253)
    - Rank, Otto Wahrheit und Wirklichkeit. English Trans., [n.p.], 1929, (110 page t.ms. (carbon)) (Box 20, Folder 254)
    - Rank, Otto Wahrheit und Wirklichkeit. French translation., [n.p.], 1929, (175 page t.ms. (carbon)) (Box 20, Folder 255)
    - Rank, Otto Wahrheit und Wirklichheit. English translation., [n.p.], 1929, (78 page t.ms.) (Box 20, Folder 256)
    - Rank, Otto Wahrheit und Wirklichheit. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1929, (7 page Newspaper clippings) (Box 20, Folder 257)
      [Gift of Estelle B. R. Simon, 1990]
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube und Psychologie., [n.p.], 1930, (185 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 21, Folder 258)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube und Psychologie. Notes., [n.p.], 1930, (1 page a.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 259)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube und Psychologie. Intro. French trans., [n.p.], 1930, (19 page t.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 260)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube und Psychologie. Loose notes and clippings., [n.p.], 1930, (15 page a.ms. & newspaper clippings) (Box 21, Folder 261)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube und Psychologie. English translation., [n.p.], 1930, (275 page t.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 262)
      [1986 gift]
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube und Psychologie. Intro. French trans., [n.p.], 1930, (23 page t.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 263)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube und Psychologie. Intro. French trans., [n.p.], 1930, (19 page t.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 264)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube und Psychologie. Loose notes in French., [n.p.], 1930, (31 page a.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 265)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube. Introduction., [n.p.], [n.d.], (15 page a.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 265a)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube. Introduction., [n.p.], [n.d.], (15 page t.ms. ) (Box 21, Folder 265b)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube. Introduction., [n.p.], [n.d.], (16 page t.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 265c)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube. Ch. 4., [n.p.], [n.d.], (10 page t.ms. & a.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 265d)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube. Ch. 3. Individualismus und Kallektivismus., [n.p.], [n.d.], (15 page a.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 265e)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube und Psychologie. Introduction., [n.p.], [n.d.], (10 page a.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 265f)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube. Loose pages., [n.p.], [n.d.], (4 page t.ms. & a.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 265g)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube. Loose pages., [n.p.], [n.d.], (8 page t.ms. & a.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 265h)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube. Gershopf und Schopfer., [n.p.], [n.d.], (14 page a.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 265i)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube. Notes., [n.p.], [n.d.], (50 page a.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 265j)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube. Notes., [n.p.], [n.d.], (25 page a.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 265k)
    - Rank, Otto Notes on Seelengluabe and Freud, [n.p.], [n.d.], (15 page t.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 265l)
    - Rank, Otto Seelenglaube. English translation of intro, chs. 1-4., [n.p.], [n.d.], (175 page t.ms.) (Box 21, Folder 265m)
    - Rank, Otto Literary autobiography, [n.p.], 1930, (27 page t.ms. (carbon)) (Box 22, Folder 266)
    - Rank, Otto Literary autobiography, [n.p.], 1930, (41 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 267)
      [Gift of the O.R.A. 1984]
    - Rank, Otto Modern Education, [n.p.], 1932, (25 page a.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 268)
    - Rank, Otto Modern Education. Ch. 2, 3, 7., [n.p.], 1932, (44 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 269)
    - Rank, Otto Development of Emotional Life. (Ch. 2 of Modern Education), [n.p.], 1930, (21 page t.ms. (page proof)) (Box 22, Folder 270)
    - Rank, Otto Development of Emotional Life. Pamphlet., [n.p.], 1930, (21 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 271)
    - Rank, Otto Modern Education. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1932, (100 page a.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 272)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Draft. Ch: Leben und Schaffen, [n.p.], 1932, (7 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 273)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Draft. Ch: Kunstform und Ideologie., [n.p.], 1932, (17 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 274)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Draft. Ch: Der Spieltrieb unde die asthetische Lust., [n.p.], 1932, (15 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 275)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Misc. Draft., [n.p.], 1932, (13 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 22, Folder 276)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Misc., [n.p.], 1932, (19 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 277)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Intro., [n.p.], 1932, (30 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 278)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 1., [n.p.], 1932, (32 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 279)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 2., [n.p.], 1932, (28 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 280)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 3., [n.p.], 1932, (18 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 281)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 5, [n.p.], 1932, (43 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 282)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 4., [n.p.], 1932, (18 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 283)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 6., [n.p.], 1932, (40 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 284)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 7., [n.p.], 1932, (24 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 285)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 8., [n.p.], 1932, (30 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 286)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 9., [n.p.], 1932, (31 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 287)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 10., [n.p.], 1932, (23 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 288)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 11., [n.p.], 1932, (26 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 289)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 12., [n.p.], 1932, (27 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 290)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 13., [n.p.], 1932, (19 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 291)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 14., [n.p.], 1932, (19 page t.ms.) (Box 22, Folder 292)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Intro., [n.p.], 1932, (28 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 22, Folder 293)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 1., [n.p.], 1932, (33 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 22, Folder 294)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 3., [n.p.], 1932, (18 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 22, Folder 295)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 4., [n.p.], 1932, (19 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 22, Folder 296)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 5., [n.p.], 1932, (60 page t.ms. & a.ms.) (Box 23, Folder 297)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 6., [n.p.], 1932, (40 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 23, Folder 298)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 7., [n.p.], 1932, (24 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 23, Folder 299)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 8., [n.p.], 1932, (30 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 23, Folder 300)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 9., [n.p.], 1932, (31 page t.ms. (carbon)) (Box 23, Folder 301)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 10., [n.p.], 1932, (23 page t.ms.) (Box 23, Folder 302)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 11., [n.p.], 1932, (33 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 23, Folder 303)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 12., [n.p.], 1932, (27 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 23, Folder 304)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 13., [n.p.], 1932, (19 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 23, Folder 305)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch. 14., [n.p.], 1932, (19 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 23, Folder 306)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ch: Mikroksomos und Makrokosmos., [n.p.], 1932, (25 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 23, Folder 307)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1932, (150 page a.ms.) (Box 23, Folder 308)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Loose notes., [n.p.], 1932, (35 page a.ms.) (Box 23, Folder 309)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Ornamentik. Notes., [n.p.], 1932, (20 page a.ms. & newspaper clippings) (Box 23, Folder 310)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Baukunst. Notes., [n.p.], 1932, (10 page a.ms.) (Box 23, Folder 311)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Religion. Notes., [n.p.], 1932, (4 page a.ms.) (Box 23, Folder 312)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Mikrokosmos. Notes., [n.p.], 1932, (5 page a.ms.) (Box 23, Folder 313)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Clippings on Aesthetic., [n.p.], 1930-1932, (7 page newspaper clippings) (Box 23, Folder 314)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Clippings on Archaeology and Anthropology., [n.p.], 1930-1932, (20 page newspaper clippings) (Box 23, Folder 315)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Clippings on paintings., [n.p.], 1930-1932, (7 page newspaper clippings) (Box 23, Folder 316)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Clippings 1931-1932., [n.p.], 1931-1932, (22 page newspaper clippings) (Box 23, Folder 317)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Clippings 1933-1934., [n.p.], 1933-1934, (17 page newspaper clippings) (Box 23, Folder 318)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Clippings 1932., (22 page newspaper clippings) (Box 23, Folder 319)
    - Rank, Otto Kunst und Kunstler. Illustrations., [n.p.], 1932, (28 pieces p.c. &magazine clippings) (Box 23, Folder 320)
    - Rank, Otto Beyond Psychology. Preface., [n.p.], 1941, (11 page a.ms.) (Box 23, Folder 321)
    - Rank, Otto Beyond Psychology. Preface., [n.p.], 1941, (17 page t.ms. &a.ms.) (Box 23, Folder 322)
    - Rank, Otto Beyond Psychology. Notes., [n.p.], 1941, (25 page a.ms.) (Box 23, Folder 323)
  - Subseries IV.2: Lectures
    - Rank, Otto Activitat., New York PSA, Jan 1925, (21 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 324)
    - Rank, Otto Activity and Passivity in Social Case Work., [n.p.], 21 Feb 1935, (6 page a.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 325)
    - Rank, Otto Activity and Passivity in Social Case Work., [n.p.], 9 April 1935, (6 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 326)
    - Rank, Otto Definition of Therapy., Jewish School of Social Work, (3 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 327)
    - Rank, Otto Differentiat between: general, experimental, ..., (14 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 328)
    - Rank, Otto The Development of the Emotional Life, [n.p.], May 1930, (9 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 329)
      [Gift of O.R.A. 1984]
    - Rank, Otto Education: Its Historical and Psychological Significance., (2 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 24, Folder 330)
    - Rank, Otto Education: Its Historical..., (2 page t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 24, Folder 331)
    - Rank, Otto Emotion and Denial, (14 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 332)
    - Rank, Otto The Essence of the psychoanalytic therapy, [n.p.], 27 May 1924, (10 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 333)
    - Rank, Otto Zur Genere der Gentalitat, (17 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 334)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psych I. 4 lectures., Philadelphia School of Social Work, (48 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 335)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie., (19 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 24, Folder 336)
    - Rank, Otto Genetische Psychologie., [n.p.], Sept.1925, (56 p (2 copies). t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 337)
    - Rank, Otto Healer's Healing, (18 page a.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 338)
    - Rank, Otto Healer's Healing, [n.p.], 19 July 1934, (28 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 339)
    - Rank, Otto [I like the idea...], [n.p.], 8 May 1935, (4 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 24, Folder 340)
    - Rank, Otto Meetings at Dr. Williams' house., [n.p.], Feb. 1930, (90 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 341)
    - Rank, Otto Meetings at Dr. Williams' house, [n.p.], March-April 1930, (95 pages) (Box 24, Folder 342)
    - Rank, Otto Modern Education. 2 lectures., [n.p.], 1928, (21 page t.ms. (pamphlet)) (Box 24, Folder 343)
    - Rank, Otto Modern Psychology and Social Change. Notes., [n.p.], 3 Feb. 1935, (9 page a.ms. &t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 344)
    - Rank, Otto Modern Psychology, University of Minnesota, 3 Feb. 1935, (35 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 345)
    - Rank, Otto Modern Psychology. Clipping., [n.p.], 6 Feb. 1935, (1 page newspaper clipping) (Box 24, Folder 346)
    - Rank, Otto Problems and Procedures, [n.p.], 21 Nov. 1934, (4 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 347)
    - Rank, Otto Psychoanalysis of Organic Conditions, [n.p.], 6 Aug. 1924, (15 page t.ms. (pamphlet)) (Box 24, Folder 348)
    - Rank, Otto Psychoanalysis of Organic Conditions, [n.p.], 6 Aug. 1924, (56 page t.ms. (journal)) (Box 24, Folder 349)
    - Rank, Otto Psychology and belief in the soul, Pennsylvania School of Social Work, 9 March 1936, (32 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 350)
    - Rank, Otto Psychology and belief in the soul., Pennsylvania School of Social Work, 9 March 1936 (Box 24, Folder 351)
    - Rank, Otto Psychology and Social Change, Paris, Jan. 1935, (20 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 352)
    - Rank, Otto Psychology and Social Change, Paris Psychological Center, July 1934, (16 page t.ms. (pamphlet)) (Box 24, Folder 353)
    - Rank, Otto Self-inflicted Ilness and Cure, [n.p.], 9 Feb. 1935, (30 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 354)
    - Rank, Otto The Practical Bearing..., [n.p.], 1924, (13 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 24, Folder 355)
    - Rank, Otto The Psychological Approach to Personal Problems, Yale, 28 Feb. 1929, (31 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 24, Folder 356)
    - Rank, Otto The Psychological Approach to Personal Problems. Minutes of the discussion., [n.p.], 28 Feb. 1929, (61 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 357)
    - Rank, Otto The Psychological Approach to Personal Problems, Yale, 28 Feb. 1929, (100 page t.ms.) (Box 24, Folder 358)
    - Rank, Otto [Redner geht aus der Tatsache...], (5 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 25, Folder 359)
    - Rank, Otto Self-inflicted illness, California Academy of Medicine, 9 Feb. 1935, (10 page t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 25, Folder 360)
      [See folder #354, box 24 for related lecture]
    - Rank, Otto The Significance of the Love Life, Philadelphia, (14 page t.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 361)
    - Rank, Otto The Symbols of Government, Pennsylvania School of Social Work, 1937-1938, (20 page t.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 362)
    - Rank, Otto The Symbols of Government, Pennsylvania School of Social Work, 1938, (25 page t.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 363)
    - Rank, Otto The Therapeutic Approach to the Neuroses, Pennsylvania School of Social Work, 25 Feb. 1928, (2 page t.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 364)
    - Rank, Otto Therapeutic Approach to the Neuroses. Rough notes., Philadelphia, 25 Feb 19[?], (2 page t.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 364a)
    - Rank, Otto Therapy Course, Jewish School of Social Work, (13 page a.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 365)
    - Rank, Otto Therapy Not Based on Causality. Course., [n.p.], 19 Dec. 1934, (3 page t.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 366)
    - Rank, Otto The Trauma of Birth. Lecture., [n.p.], 3 June 1924, (6 page t.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 367)
    - Rank, Otto The Trauma of Birth, [n.p.], 3 June 1924, (4 page t.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 368)
    - Rank, Otto Das Verhaeltnis der elterlichen Einstellung zu Erfolg, New York, 2 Nov. 1927, (13 page t.ms. (carbons)) (Box 25, Folder 369)
    - Rank, Otto [When I was asked...], New York School of Social Work, 16 Nov. 1935, (11 page t.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 370)
    - Rank, Otto Lecture at Yale, New Haven, Conn., [n.d.], (2 page t.ms. &a.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 370a)
    - Announcements of lectures 1924-1936, [n.p.], 1924-1936, (18 page t.ms. (brochures)) (Box 25, Folder 371)
    - Two brochures announcing Rank's lectures at PSSW, [n.p.], 1927 and 1928, (4 pages) (Box 25, Folder 371a)
    - Rank, Otto Notebook and notes on the 1924 lectures, [n.p.], 1924, (8 page a.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 372)
    - Rank, Otto Courses at Pennsylvania School of Social Work 1928 & 1934, Pennsylvania School of Social Work, 1928 & 1934, (9 page a.ms. &t.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 373)
    - The Psychological Center Report on the 1934 Summer Session, Paris, Jan. 1935, (12 page t.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 374)
    - Rank, Otto Notebook of lectures, (6 page a.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 375)
    - Rank, Otto Lecture at the Psychological Center. Notes., (9 page a.ms. &t.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 376)
    - Otto Rank Association Brochure of O.R.A. of North Carolina, Raleigh, North Carolina, 4 May 1984, (4 page t.ms.) (Box 25, Folder 376a)
  - Subseries IV.3: Book Reviews
    - Book Review of Beyond Psychology, (4 page t.ms.) (Box 26, Folder 377)
    - Book Review of Der Doppelganger, [n.p.], 16 May 1914, (2 page newspaper clippings) (Box 26, Folder 378)
    - Alex&er, Franz Book Review of Entwicklungsziele, [n.p.], 1924, (4 page t.ms.) (Box 26, Folder 379)
    - Book Review of Entwicklungsziele, [n.p.], Jan 1929, (64 page t.ms. (journal)) (Box 26, Folder 380)
    - Book Review of Entwicklungsziele, (2 page t.ms.) (Box 26, Folder 381)
    - Entwicklungsziele. List of book reviews., (1 page a.ms.) (Box 26, Folder 382)
    - Book Review of Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 1912-1936, (15 page t.ms.) (Box 26, Folder 383)
    - Book Review of Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], Jan. 1913, (60 page t.ms. (journal)) (Box 26, Folder 384)
    - Book Review of Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 5 July 1913, (10 page t.ms. (journal)) (Box 26, Folder 385)
    - Book Review of Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], July 1913, (145 page t.ms. (journal)) (Box 26, Folder 386)
    - Book Review of Inzest-Motiv, [n.p.], 3 Aug. 1913, (8 p (2 copies). t.ms.) (Box 26, Folder 387)
    - Book Review of Der Kunstler, [n.p.], 1907-1925, (10 page t.ms. (clippings)) (Box 26, Folder 388)
    - Rank, Otto Book Review of Der Kunstler, [n.p.], 1907, (48 page t.ms. (journal)) (Box 26, Folder 389)
    - Rank, Otto Book Review of Lohengrinsage, [n.p.], 1911, (4 page t.ms. &a.ms.) (Box 26, Folder 390)
    - Book Review of Der Mythus. Lohengrinsage., [n.p.], 1918, (60 page t.ms. (journal)) (Box 26, Folder 391)
    - Stekel, Wilhelm Book Review of Der Mythus, [n.p.], 5 Sept. 1910, (2 page newspaper clippings) (Box 26, Folder 392)
    - Book Review of Der Mythus, [n.p.], Jan.-April 1921, (72 page t.ms. (journal)) (Box 26, Folder 393)
    - (Box 26, Folder 394)
      [Mistakenly created folder]
    - Rank, Otto Book Review of Der Mythus, [n.p.], 1909, (3 page a.ms.) (Box 26, Folder 395)
    - Book Review of Psychoanalytische Beitrage, [n.p.], 1919, (1 page a.ms.) (Box 26, Folder 396)
    - Book Review of Psychoanalytische Beitrage, [n.p.], 1921, (22 page t.ms. (journal)) (Box 26, Folder 397)
    - Book Review of Die Psychoanalytische Methode, (2 page t.ms.) (Box 26, Folder 398)